- Okay. - One!
- One! - Close. Ready, and two! Shit!
- Right, ready. - Let's go again.
- Zero! - [groans]
Yeah!
That's it, I win. Pay up.
- Let's go again. - I already beat you. No.
- Double or nothing, man! - [resident 1] No, I'm done!
[resident 2] Come on, one more. Don't tell me you're chicken?
[resident 1] I know I can beat you.
[ominous music droning]
I got four today.
You sure you wanna do it like this? It's the only way?
[man sighs] There's no problem, all right? Look.
We've already reinforced the tunnel
METEORITE IMPACT POINT
Right under the meteorite. We place the bomb here, and we blow it up.
It'll collapse the whole cave
And the meteorite will end up buried deep underground.
I told you, no problem.
Doesn't sound like no problem. Come on!
Do you understand how many people we've already lost?
Hey, relax. No one cares.
Let's get this done and keep our mouths shut.
They want more people, I'll bring 'em more.
[Obata] How can you talk like that?
Don't walk away!
Our orders are coming from the very top.
Do us all a favor and keep your personal views to yourself.
We've got a job to do, so get to work.
[Obata] Damn it.
I can't believe this.
[ominous music building]
- [man 1] Okay, everyone, put these on. - [music fades out]
CHILDREN OF THE WORLD PEACE EXPO '99
[man 2] Come on, put the masks on.
Hurry. Don't make me tell you a second time.
Walk for about half a mile, then you'll reach a cave.
You'll see the meteorite from there. The job's simple.
All you have to do is leave this at the cave entrance.
A monkey could do it.
Easy.
Hey!
If you do this, and you do it right, you're going to walk away filthy rich.
Tell me that doesn't appeal to you.
Just get it done.
[man 1] All right, everyone!
[resident 1] Okay, I'm going in first.
[resident 2] Always hogging the glory, aren't you, Shortstack?
[resident 1] Only 'cause you're too busy pissing your pants in fear.
[man 1] All right, stop squabbling and be careful with the thing!
- [Ren] You okay? - [resident 3] Yeah.
[man 2] Hey. Stop slacking and get yours on too.
You wouldn't want the little princess to worry, would you?
[man 1] Can you handle that? It's pretty heavy.
- Good luck in there! - [resident 3 grunts]
- [man 1] Watch where you step. - [man 2] Make sure they don't try to run.
WATCH OUT FOR FORK IN THE ROAD!
3/8 ARRIVAL AT IMPACT POINT
[exhausted groaning]
[chilling music playing]
[resident groaning wearily]
[Ren breathing anxiously]
[resident gasping, wheezing]
[crunching underfoot]
[Ren whimpering]
[gasping]
[panicked breathing]
[wheezing]
[music becomes sinister]
[shattering, crumbling]
[Ren breathing raggedly]
[gagging, coughing]
[Ren panting]
[gasping]
[unsettling pulsating, high-pitched tone]
[pulsating tone becoming stronger]
[Ren wheezes]
[panicked breathing]
[grunting]
[choking]
[Ren screaming]
[klaxon blares]
- What? - [klaxon blares]
Wait, don't tell me they actually
There is no way
It's happening! We're finally done!
[yells excitedly]
Okay, let's blow it up! Let's go! Hit it!
No, no, no, we can't!
There's still people in there. You'll kill them! Don't do it!
- [shouting outside] - [frantic, tense music playing]
[man, outside] Do it, goddammit!
[Sano hesitating]
Uh?
- [rapid footsteps] - [Ren choking]
[panting]
[tense, dramatic music playing]
- [Obata] No, don't do it! - Hey, look! Look!
[Ren gasping, choking]
[man grunting]
- [Ren choking] - [man grunting]
Get the hell off me!
[Ren groaning]
[pained yelling]
Help me! [screaming]
[Sano] Just fucking do it.
[Ren screaming]
[explosion echoing]
[dark, dramatic music playing]
HUMAN VAPOR
The body of Police Superintendent General Sakamoto
has been located by police in a parked car in Minato Ward.
Ms. Araki is live now.
Just behind me is the site of the gruesome discovery
earlier tonight.
[concerned chattering]
[Araki] Superintendent General Sakamoto was found dead
in the black car you can see just behind me.
Police have cordoned off the scene.
Just hours before the body was found,
the Human Vapor had announced his intention to kill Sakamoto
via a live stream channel
[phone ringing out]
KAHO, TERROR ZONE
[Kyoko sighs]
"Kaho, has anything happened? Are you okay? Call me."
[phone buzzes]
"I'm fine, call you later."
- [Kaho grunting] - [man 1] Stop it! Come on!
- [man 2] Hold still, damn it! - [Kaho] Give me my phone!
[man 1] Shut up, shut up!
Ah! She bit me, what the fuck?!
- Get over here! - Hey!
Tie her up, quick!
- [Riki] Like you should've done first! - Sorry, Riki.
- [man 3] Stop making trouble, got it? - [Kaho] Let go of me!
[Riki] We just wanna know who this is. Who sent you this message?
[man 3] Answer the boss, now!
So, Okamoto
What did you talk about with the superintendent general?
What, you deaf now?
We need to know what the man said to you right before he killed himself.
- Killed himself? - Yeah.
After the Human Vapor's video.
No wonder he felt there was no way out.
You did it! It was you!
You killed him, and you made it look like a suicide!
- Didn't you? Didn't you?! - [Michiko] Let him go!
- Fuckin' crazy! - [Michiko] Let him go, damn it!
[chief] Are you out of your goddamn mind?
[Kenji panting]
What's wrong with you?
One more step out of line, and you're outta here.
Yoshida's just trying to figure out what happened.
We've got nothing to go on. No cameras at the crime scene.
And because of that, we
Without better evidence, we have to treat this as suicide.
[Kenji breathes heavily]
[Kenji sighs]
The last thing the man said
Was that we should all go out for dinner again.
That's all he said.
[sighs]
There was a sadness behind his eyes.
They looked like the eyes of a man who was going to take his own life.
That good enough for you?
That's real cute, Detective.
[chief] He's a loose cannon. We gotta rein him in.
[tense music playing]
[doors unlocking]
[footsteps approaching]
[breathing heavily]
[melancholy music playing]
[bangs fist]
[exhales]
[Sakamoto] Kenji.
There's something else you should know.
Your father
I'm responsible for his death.
[Chieko] My husband had a strong sense of justice.
- I hope he'll be remembered for that. - [reporter 1] Did you find documents
[Tatsuya] It's awful, putting her through this.
I mean, he just died.
[reporter 2] Do you think the threat led to his suicide?
[Tatsuya] No wonder people hate the media.
Here. You should eat something.
[reporter 3] Did he get along with colleagues?
It seemed like the two of them were really in love.
Apparently they met at school.
[reporter 4] Did he tell you anything pertaining to the case?
- Was your husband afraid? - Was there really no suicide note?
[reporters all speak at once]
Whoa, what's wrong?
- [Chieko] Nothing else was found. - [reporter 5] Has a search been done?
[reporters continue questioning]
I'm going out for a bit.
Oh, okay.
Oh-ho!
Oh
Sh
4.01 MILLION VIEWS
[gasping]
[calm music playing]
[music fades out]
Kaho!
It's a great day for believers!
Guess what?
I scored four unsold bento boxes!
Kaho?
- [Kaho whimpers] - Hey, buddy.
- [dramatic music playing] - [grunting]
Kaho!
[men grunting]
- [man 1] Stop! - [Fujita] Kaho!
- [man 2] You're making it worse! - [Kaho yelling]
[man 1] Hey!
[grunting]
- [man 1] Hey! - [man 2] Come back!
- [man 3] Shit! - [man 2] You little--
[man 1] I'm gonna kick your ass!
[Fujita grunting]
[man 1 yells]
[Fujita] Kaho!
[Kaho whimpering]
- I got you. I got you! - [Riki] Fujita!
[Kaho screaming]
[Fujita groans]
- [Riki] And stay down! - [Kaho squeals]
[Fujita grunts]
[groaning]
[Riki] Both so stubborn. No wonder you're brother and sister.
A waste of our precious time.
- Tie him up. - [man 2] Yes, sir.
[Kaho whimpering]
[Riki] And you, shut up.
[music fades out]
COMMENDATION ASSISTANT INSPECTOR SHINYA OKAMOTO
[mournful music playing]
[sighs sadly]
CHILDREN OF THE WORLD PEACE EXPO '99
[Sakamoto] Listen.
I know all about your current investigation.
[Shinya] What are you trying to say?
[music fades out]
Just that [sighs]
[Shinya sniffs]
It runs deeper than you think. Trust me, I know.
[Shinya] Hmm.
What do you mean,
You know?
[Sakamoto] You're investigating that facility,
And you've uncovered things better left buried.
And now you're after that yakuza too.
Does that mean you know
What they're doing to people at that center?
[Sakamoto sighs]
Yeah.
All I'm saying is just stay out of it.
[Shinya breathes deeply]
Stay out of it?
Sakamoto,
Do you have any idea what you're asking me to do?
[Sakamoto] Do you have any idea who these people are?
These aren't just criminals.
If you know their names,
You already know too much.
So I just back off?
No matter who we're facing down,
It's our job and our responsibility to uncover the truth, no matter the cost.
Am I wrong?
[doleful music playing]
[Shinya sighs]
Give us a minute, Kenji.
[door closing]
[Kenji breathing anxiously]
[Kenji] What happened to my dad?
[Sakamoto] He was chasing a fleeing suspect.
A truck came out of nowhere and hit him.
Dad?
Come on!
Dad, wake up!
Please
[music becomes mysterious]
ABOUT WHITE CENTER: IT PROVIDES JOBS TO PEOPLE IN NEED
YASUTOSHI MORI PHYSICAL FEATURES: SNAKE TATTOO ON WRIST
[Mori] I knew an Okamoto once. What are you, his son?
The two of us, we go way back, your old man and I.
No, he wasn't so smart in the end.
Such a tragedy.
[croaks]
[tense music playing]
[dramatic drumbeats pounding]
[music fades out]
[man 1] Start talking, nerd boy!
You brought this on yourself!
Now you know what happens when you keep your mouth shut!
You know I could kill you!
[Fujita gasping]
[man 1] Come on!
- Ka Kaho! Kaho! - [Riki] Fujita
- [Fujita] Get away from her! - Should I cut off your sister's mark?
I could do it so nice and clean with my knife.
No, no, no! Leave her alone! You piece of shit!
[Riki] Look, my friend,
If you'll just tell us what we wanna know,
I'll let both of you walk free, simple as that.
- Okay? - [Fujita panting]
- [Kaho] Fujita! - How'd you get this video?
Why did the Human Vapor send it to you, huh?
Don't tell him anything, Fujita!
[suspenseful music playing]
Please! Don't do it!
- Well? - The Human Vapor
- Yeah - [Kaho] No! Stop!
It's possible to control him.
Fujita!
[whimpering]
[Fujita] I gave an order to the Human Vapor.
I was the one who took the video.
[Riki laughing]
"Gave an order"? Show me how you did it.
[music stops]
EVIDENCE STORAGE ROOM 5
Through here.
Thanks.
[determined music playing]
"Yasutoshi Mori, aged 54."
"Ligature on neck from bathrobe belt."
"Minor chemical burns present in both lungs."
[Michiko] Kyugo Sano, professor of environmental engineering.
There were severe thermal injuries on the inner lung tissue,
more consistent with chemical burns
than those typically caused by high temperatures.
[Kenji] "Fujishiro Syndicate members."
Saburo Otomo.
Riki Otomo.
Akira Maeda.
Yasutoshi Mori.
'99
April
"Tateishi Station, assault at restaurant."
April 1999.
'70 No. '85.
"Summary of assault on manager."
"Bunko Ramen."
Bunko Ramen.
[music fades out]
[sighs]
You're trying to tell me
That my husband was involved in this?
I know it must be hard to hear.
Your husband's death wasn't a suicide.
They wanted him to pay.
This Mufu organization silenced him.
[Chieko] Mufu?
[sighs]
I'm sorry, Ms. Kono, but you must be confused.
That isn't right.
Mufu isn't some secret cabal.
So then what is it?
Mufu is a band.
My husband started a band with a few of his friends
When he was in high school.
What?
There they all are.
MUFU
CONQUER THE WHOLE WORLD! OTOMO, KAI, SAKAMOTO
Do you know the third man? It says "Kai".
[Chieko] Kai?
Oh, yes.
He was the frontman.
He doesn't look quite like that anymore.
Anymore? You still know him, then?
Oh, yes.
Takeshi Miura.
From frontman to governor. Can you imagine?
[mournful music playing]
I'm so sorry for disturbing you.
[Chieko] Hmm?
Thank you very much.
REFORM WITHOUT WASTE TO CREATE A NEW TOKYO - TAKESHI MIURA
TOKYO GOVERNOR ELECTION
[phone ringing]
- [fax machine whirring] - [mournful music continues]
[mournful music ends]
[record crackling]
["Ellie My Love" by Southern All Stars playing]
[Kyoko] "Your next target is Takeshi Miura."
"I sent his image by fax. Kill him."
SEND
[singing in Japanese] ♪ If you still want ♪
♪ My affection ♪
♪ After I've been distant, made you cry ♪
♪ I'll make you my final lady ♪
[in English] ♪ Ellie ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ So sweet ♪
MESSAGE SENT OK
[in Japanese] ♪ If one day our feelings fade ♪
♪ And turn to tender sorrow ♪
♪ If I'm left with nothing But memories of you ♪
♪ Once we're at a loss for words Love is over ♪
[in English] ♪ Ellie ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ So sweet ♪
[in Japanese] ♪ Smile for me, baby So innocently on my mind ♪
♪ Let yourself shine, baby So lovely in your sight ♪
♪ The day of beckoning tears Sets with the sun ♪
[in English] ♪ Ellie, my ♪
[music stops]
Now, that is a damn good song.
[automated voice] Your target is Takeshi Miura.
I sent his image by fax. Kill him.
Oh You wanna tell me why this song started playing?
- Huh? Fuckin' tell me. - [Kaho] Stop!
[Fujita] Please, sir! Don't hurt me
- [Kaho] Fujita! - [Fujita grunts]
- [Kaho whimpering] - [Fujita grunting]
- [Riki] You wanna live? - [Fujita coughing]
Then stop begging and tell me how the fuck I make him obey orders!
Don't hurt her!
[man] Hey, hey, hey! Take a breath!
[eerie music playing]
There's no need to rush.
Whoa.
This is incredible.
Take your men and wait outside.
Are you sure, boss? This guy might have more fight in him.
I said get the fuck out.
Let's go.
[eerie music builds, then fades out]
[Kyoko] "Kenji, where are you? We need to talk."
[Fujita panting]
[Miura] I have a story for you.
I heard it when I was traveling in Ecuador, of all places.
Miguel was a young Ecuadorian man,
Who worked on a coffee plantation.
Then one day,
The plantation's owner died.
And Miguel was the one who inherited the land and the plantation.
Lucky guy.
What do you think Miguel did next?
He sold it.
Sold off the plantation and much of that land,
And built himself a mansion.
- [tense music playing] - And it was glorious.
He lived a life of luxury in that mansion, you understand?
What he didn't know
Is that his house
Was built on ground that was unsuitable for construction.
And when the spring floods eventually came,
It was washed away,
And lucky Miguel right along with it.
The soil was perfect for producing coffee beans,
But that's all it was good for.
Poor lucky Miguel.
The moral of this story
Is that it's tragic to take advantage of something
Without understanding its value.
So, tell me how we control him.
[Fujita breathing shakily]
[Fujita hesitates, sniffs]
[nervously] First First you, uh
You use that.
You play "Ellie My Love"
On the record player over there.
And that's it.
He'll sort of come to life. [sniffs]
So you just You tell him what to do.
That's all I know. [sniffs]
I think he'll do what you say, as long as he understands it.
Please, I
- Kaho, let's go-- - [Miura] Wait.
First things first.
I need to try it.
You wanna end up like Miguel?
[music fades out]
- [owner] Hey! Come on in. - How you doing?
[owner] Good, yeah.
What's the matter? I'm right about to close.
- You wanna eat? Grab a stool. - No, that's all right.
I'm with the police.
[owner sighs] Again?
Is this about that Human Vapor thing?
- Shit. - [Kenji] No, no.
It's about Bunko Ramen, the old one. I had a few questions.
[owner] Man, come on
I don't know anything about it, okay?
You don't know anything?
I wasn't planning on running a ramen shop. It was my dad's place.
I wanted to be a manga artist.
I did a few.
Run Away! Miso Ramen Man. That was my first one.
But everyone said it was lame and unoriginal, so I just gave it up.
Look, do you know if anyone who comes here
Was maybe a regular when your dad ran the restaurant?
[owner] Nah, I don't know.
Sometimes people come in to look at the Polaroids over there.
My dad would post pics of customers on the wall.
They're not mine, but I couldn't just throw them away,
So I put them up. Call it a link to the past.
[haunting music playing]
[sighs] I'm closing up, man, so if you're not gonna eat
Yeah, okay. I'll take a bowl.
You got it.
It's on the house.
♪ Ellie ♪
♪ My love ♪
- ♪ So sweet ♪ - Whoa
[Human Vapor] Listener,
Please,
Make a wish.
[Miura] So now I just say my wish?
- Yeah. - [Miura] Wonderful.
You two are free to go.
♪ So sweet ♪
♪ Ellie ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ So sweet ♪
I got a wish for ya.
Kill those kids.
Kaho, run!
[dramatic music playing]
- [Kaho panting] - Come on, hurry!
- [man 1] I said stop! - [man 2] Get back, you little shit!
[man 3] Stop them!
[man 4] What the hell? Stop!
- [Kaho] Get off me! - [Fujita] Son of a bitch!
[man 5] What are you doing? Get them!
- [man 6] Huh? - [man 7] Don't move!
[Miura laughing]
What a vision, huh?
- Kaito! - Let's get 'em!
Wait!
They're not worth it.
They won't survive long anyway.
[Kaho panting]
[Kaho shrieks]
- [Fujita] Come on, come on - [Kaho] Hurry! Drive! Go, go, go!
Hold on!
[both screaming]
- [Fujita yells] - Look out!
[Fujita yells]
- You're gonna get us both killed! - We'll be fine! We can do this!
[Kaho whimpering]
[Kaho breathing anxiously]
[tires screech]
CAR RENTAL REFUELING
[Kaho] What are you doing?
[Fujita grunting]
[attendant] What the hell dude? You got a death wish?!
Fujita, what the hell is going on?!
- He's He's here! Hurry! Run! - Come on! Come on!
[Kaho shrieks]
[both panting]
- What are you Stop! - [Fujita grunting]
Put me down, I can still run!
[Kaho shrieks]
[Kaho screaming]
[Kaho gasping] Fujita!
- Swim, Kaho! Get outta here! Go! - Fujita!
Get outta here! Go!
- [Fujita screams] - Fujita!
Fujita!
[Kaho screams] No!
Fujita! [gasps]
No, wait!
[Fujita choking]
[Kaho screams] No!
No! Fujita!
[coughing] Fujita!
[Fujita choking]
- [music stops] - [Kaho screams] No! No!
[whimpering]
[spluttering]
[whooshing, gurgling]
KYOKO AND REN
[poignant music playing]
[music distorts, fades]
[footsteps approaching slowly]
[poignant music resumes]
[Kyoko sighs sadly]
I was hoping to be the one to tell you.
Kenji.
You know, don't you?
[newscaster] Breaking news.
The Metropolitan Police Department has issued an all-points bulletin
for JNT reporter Kyoko Kono,
who they say is involved in the Human Vapor case.
A police spokesperson told press earlier today
that Ms. Kono recently became a person of interest
in the string of murders in Tokyo.
They allege that the reporter issued orders to the Human Vapor
and incited him to commit the crimes in question.
Kono has been missing since yesterday,
and the Metropolitan Police Department
is asking the public for help in locating her.
The killings began earlier this month
when, during an interview with Ms. Kono on JNT,
Professor Sano was murdered during a live broadcast.
Since then, the list of victims has increased at an alarming rate.
The police remind the public that Ms. Kono should be considered dangerous,
and that if you see her, to call the authorities.
You wouldn't mind an extra slice of chashu pork, would you now?
Where'd he go?
[dramatic, emotional music playing]
[dramatic, emotional music continues]
[Kaho gasping]
[panting]
[whimpering]
[music softens]
[crying]
[panicked breathing]
[screams]
[dramatic music playing]